Denise Ortega

I am a detail-oriented, design-driven full stack web developer. My background as an engineer allows me to approach problems abstractly and conquer them efficiently, while my experience as a program manager allows me to plan and implement for scale, while setting realistic goals.

Seattle, WA, dddotcom@gmail.com

LinkedIn: /ddortega Github: /dddotcom URL: dddotcom.github.io

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Ruby, SQL, Bash

Tools/Frameworks:

Express, Angular, Rails, Node,
PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Git,
Heroku, Bootstrap

Experience

Microsoft, Redmond, WA - Program Manager

Aug 2015 - Oct 2016

Design and oversee implementation of a Cloud Infrastructure deployment tool. Meet with subject-matter-experts to accurately document the infrastructure deployment process flow. Help prioritize engineering work, engage with stakeholders to track progress, and verify completeness.

Lumenpulse, Boston, MA - Application Developer

Nov 2014 - May 2015

Develop an Android application that controls the brightness and color of Lumenpulse light fixtures over Bluetooth Low Energy. Test the functionality and user experience with the customer before the app was revealed at Lightfair 2015.

MITRE, Bedford, MA - Cyber Infrastructure Intern

May 2014 - Nov 2014

Develop a Grails web application that provisions Virtual Machines according to customer specifications by utilizing the VMware API. The application eliminates ambiguous requests and increases VM provisioning throughput through automation.

CIDAR Lab, Boston, MA - Software Developer

May 2014 - Nov 2014

Work on a team to develop a Java application for automating Synthetic Biology protocols. Devised a graph algorithm that uses custom data structures to accurately schedule and reserve laboratory equipment.

Projects

Tanya Wenya Teens, - Web based two-player game

A game inspired by Tenya Wanya Teens, built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Phaser.io. TWT is a two player game where players race to complete tasks such as brushing their teeth or playing guitar.

Tinder 4 Animals, - Remake of the Tinder dating app, with a twist

A full-stack web app built with Express and PostgreSQL that utilizes both Local and Facebook authorization schemes. The application logic and database structure enables users to "like", "dislike", "match" with, and chat with other users.

Cards Against Humanatee, - Online version of Cards Against Humanity

Worked on a team to build A MEAN stack app that utilizes sockets to create online game rooms and sync game play amongst multiple users. Responsible for database model and backend architecture and implementation. Assisted in socket implementation.

The Guardian, - Senior Capstone Project

A baby monitoring system that uses a raspberry pi, temperature sensors, and a raspicam to stream live video and data to a Rails application. Responsible for implementing the communication layer between the devices and web application. Designed and implemented an efficient live-streaming solution, minimizing playback latency to 5-7 seconds.

Education

General Assembly, Seattle, WA

February 2017 - April 2017

A full time, 12-week course teaching programming fundamentals and skills to build full-stack web applications.

Boston University, Boston, WA - Computer Engineering BS

January 2012 - May 2015